# **Xiating Cai (John)**

Linkedin.com/in/JohnXiating

Phone: 0405 359 825 Email: John.Xiating@gmail.com Portfolio: JohnX.co

After travelling across the US, UK, South Asia and the east coast of Australia, and having worked in Shanghai and Sydney, I fell in love with Tasmania - a peaceful place to settle and create. I have experience in Services Operations, Business Analysis, Customer Care and a solid background across the Education and E-learning industry. I am currently living in Tasmania, whilst waiting for the approval of my 485 Post-Study Work Visa, a Bridging A Visa has been granted allowing me to work full time unrestricted.

# **Education**

The University of Tasmania – Master of Information Management and Systems

March 2019 – December 2020

The University of Taizhou (Eastern China) – Bachelor of Physics (Teacher Education)

September 2008 – June 2012

# **Key Attributes**

**Interpersonal Skills:** Effectively collaborated across different business functions (product, service, and tech team) during two years of IT consulting roles with large complex global corporations in Shanghai, one year of Customer IT Support role in Australia, and volunteer work in California (USA).

**Initiative & Teamwork:** Started up the Virtual-study Hub project to help students to study online during the COVID-19 time; Co-founded the Multi-Cultural Club, an active University society; Delivered award-winning team projects in GovHack 2020 and UHack 2019.

**Digital Learning:** Experienced in E-learning having gained two years of working experience as a science teacher in China, one year of PASS leader (Web & Software Development) at UTAS, Australia, two years of IT Consultant role in online learning platform italki.com (Shanghai). Familiar with learning management systems and platforms such as D2L Brightspace, PebblePad, and Udemy.

# **Work Experience**

### Casual UConnect Officer | Student Services, University of Tasmania

(Feb 2021 – Present)

- Gathered the students' inquires including timetable, enrolment and account issues at the student centre, answered and redirected students to the specific services on campus.
- Managed students' information through the Client Services Officer Student Management,
  and Identity One System.

### IT Helpdesk / Administrator | Techbyte Solutions Launceston, Tasmania (Dec 2019 – Feb 2021)

- Offered IT services including remote IT support, video conferencing support, configuring networks and installing systems to customers with a range of technical understanding.
- · Utilised HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Facebook developer tools to create a business website (techbyte.net.au).

### PASS Leader | Student Retention & Success, University of Tasmania (Jan 2020 – Dec 2020)

- Designed both online and offline Peer Assisted Study Sessions (Web & Software Development) based on the students' feedback and needs. See session details here.
- Facilitated and held online sessions for a range of different university students through MyLO student learning portal, Blackboard Collaborate, and Echo 360.

## Residential Leader | Student Living Communities, University of Tasmania (Jan 2020 – Dec 2020)

- · Assisted residents on-campus to use the student learning & living portal to improve their academic and university living experience, organised events with the student living team.
- Organised cultural events that encourage international students and local students to meet each other, creating a sense of belonging in the university community.

### Udemy Instructor (Online) | Udemy.com

(Jan 2019 - Jan 2020)

• Developed a content-driven video course for learners on Udemy that reached 893 students across the world from 90 countries. Communicated with online students on the platform through the instructor dashboard. See course details at Udemy: Learn Chinese From Scratch.

#### IT Consultant | italki Office Shanghai, China

(Jul 2015 – May 2018)

- Provided consulting and IT support for online language teachers worldwide, posted monthly teacher newsletters and guides to 4000+ teachers on the platform.
- · Undertook customer satisfaction research and data analysis through the ticketing system to improve the new teacher onboarding experience and student learning experience.

# **Projects and Volunteer Experience**

#### Co-founder | Multi-Cultural Club, Tasmania

(Jun 2020 – Present)

- Co-Founded Multi-Cultural Club, utilised HTML5, JavaScript, CSS to develop a static, informational website (mcctas.com.au) that create society's online presence.
- Established the club's information structure, utilised Trello (a web-based workflow management tool) to arrange work and assign the task to committee team members.

Web Developer / Consultant | Engineering Heritage Tasmania, Australia (Jul 2020 – Oct 2020)

- · Offered a simple, lightweight solution that fits the client's need simplifying the process to allow less tech-savvy members to upload, edit the material on the site, and developed enhancements to the <u>EHTAS</u> website application (map tours).
- Created <u>guide documents</u> and <u>video guides</u> to assist members with ranges of technical knowledge.

### Project Leader | GovHack 2020, Tasmania

(Aug 2020 - Aug 2020)

 Created the Heritage Hunt project concept, led and collaborated the team won three awards in <u>GovHack 2020</u>. Designed the UI and improved the prototype for the <u>Heritage Hunt app</u>.
 See project details <u>here</u>.

### Project Leader | UHack 2019, Tasmania

(Aug 2019 – Sep 2019)

- · Created the Plastic Free Tasmania project, led the team "No Plus" won the 3rd prize in the Student Division in UHack 2019 Competition.
- · Presented a pitch that highlighted the plastic problem and the solution of "Plastic Currency".

# **Referees**

Jacob Workman Head, Student Living Communities (North & Northwest)

University of Tasmania E: Jacob.Workman@utas.edu.au P: 03 6324 3014

**Dr Kathy French** PASS Program Coordinator

University of Tasmania E: Kr.French@utas.edu.au P: 03 6226 5546

Winyu Chinthammit Degree Coordinator, Human Interface Technology (HIT Lab AU)

University of Tasmania E: Winyu.Chinthammit@utas.edu.au P: 03 6324 3975

Kellie Brandenburg Student Engagement Coordinator

University of Tasmania E: Kellie.Brandenburg@utas.edu.au P: 03 6324 9701